Fangfang Xiao | Software FullStack Developer

226-978-0590 | fxiao.mecheng@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/fangfang-xiao| Github: http://github.com/f2xiao| Portfolio: https://f2xiao.github.io/site

PROFILE

A software fullstack developer transitioned from Mechanical Engineering with 3+ years working experience in Automotive Manufacturing industry. With my unique blend of skills, including problem-solving, collaborative and coordination expertise from the manufacturing industry, I bring a fresh perspective to software engineering.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, React, Vue, Nextjs, Styled-Components, Redux

Backend: Node.js, ExpressJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Java, Python, RESTful APIs, SQL, Software development

DevOps and Tools: Docker, Microsoft Azure, GitHub, version control, Git, Webpack, Agile environment

PROJECTS

Software Fullstack Developer | NextWatch: https://next-watch.onrender.com

MAY 2024, BRAINSTATION CAPSTONE

- Deployed and launched a full stack website with React for frontend and Node Js as backend
- Designed the UI and developed it with React and TypeScript
- Integrated the backend with Express and MongoDB to facilitate user administration and data storage

Software Fullstack Developer | Instock: https://instock-frontend-0kc1.onrender.com

April 2024, BRAINSTATION Group Project

- Led a Agile team of 4 people to deliver an inventory management system within less than a week
- Reviewed teammates' code and offered support to overcome any blockers
- Managed the project by diligently updating the Jira board and promptly rectifying mislabeled tickets to ensure timely delivery

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

FEB 2024 - MAY 2024, TORONTO, ON

University of Waterloo | Bachelors in Applied Science, Mechanical Engineering Co-op

Sep 2012 - AUG 2017, WATERLOO, ON

EXPERIENCE

Technical Forging Associate | Musashi Auto Parts

APR 2019 - MAR 2020, ARTHUR, ON

- Increased production efficiencies by Implementing a visual detection system that reduced defects by 10%
- Engineered the model of a conveyor system that automated the production line by saving 10% of time
- Communicated and sourced the suppliers that meet product specs and saved a cost of 10k

Project Engineering Coop | ABC Group Inc

MAY 2015- Sept 2015, ETOBICOKE, ON

- Led and directed various internal testings of new model launch with 100% passed
- Summarized testing results and reported to customers with a result of ahead of project timeline
- Submitted the pre-production samples with necessary certificates to customers with 100% passed